[Music]
hi everyone we're here for another
episode of the usada pitch with me today
is tammy hansen our elite education
manager and since the beijing games are
right around the corner she'll be
talking about how we're educating
athletes and support personnel in
preparation for the games
tammy how is life less than 100 days out
from the start of the beijing games
hey avery the team is as busy as ever
ensuring every detail of games education
as top priority
yep of course well let's happen can you
tell everyone about some of the ways
athletes and support personnel can get
educated before going to the games
yeah i sure can so 90 days out from the
games usada will launch a beijing
specific course for those preparing to
go
this course will not required is
designed to ensure that every athlete
and athlete support person understands
the relevant anti-doping rules prior to
the 2022 games
we'll be sending out packages to each
athlete attending to the games uh this
will include game specific rules and
we'll have face-to-face education at
with many of the national teams
okay gotcha so who's providing this
education
so the elite education team and i will
be providing several face-to-face
education sessions for athletes and
athletes support people
but we also have a health professional
educator uh kelsa who joined our team
and she's going to make sure that
there's plenty of education out there
for medical providers who are going to
be supporting athletes at the games as
well
you might see some of our athlete
presenters at some of those major events
and even some of our dcos are spending
some time completing extra education in
addition to the clean sport course to
athletes during their first out of
competition tests
i love that the dcos are getting
involved with education
yeah i do too
so what can athletes and others do if
they want to support clean sport
initiatives before the games
yeah as always speaking out about clean
sport is really the best way to support
but more than that it's about being
supportive of the process when the dco
comes to test them that's really a great
way to show your support to clean sport
and paying attention to the rules and
the education that's being provided
making sure that athletes understand and
know what to expect when they go to
compete is just really important and a
great way to support clean sport
initiatives
definitely
where athletes and support personnel go
if they have questions specific to the
games
yeah so we have a game specific webpage
so if they go to the usada website
find that page and that's going to be
the best place to find game specific
education but as always we encourage
athletes to contact us directly if they
have any additional questions
at athlete express
awesome well with that i think we can
wrap it up tammy thanks so much for the
information
yeah thanks for having me it's always a
pleasure
everyone thanks for joining us and stay
tuned for the next episode of the pitch
[Music]
you